اَعُوْذُ بِاللهِ مِنَّ الشِّيْطَانِ الرَّجِيْمِ۞
بِسْمِ اللهِ الرَّحْمَانِ الرَّحِيْمَ۞
اَلْحَمْدُ لله ، وَالصَّلَاةُ وَالسَّلَامُ عَلى سَيِّدِنَا محمد وَعَلَى اَلِهِ وَصَحْبِهِ وَسَلِّمْ تَسْلِيْمًا كَثِيْرا
Continuing with the response of the people of Quraish(قُرَيْشْ) towards the message of Rasool Allah ﷺ.
We talked about a few yesterday, we'll continue with the rest.
Number eight,
they would try to put Muhammadﷺ under pressure.
They were persistent, they would never give up, they would keep on trying every method
including, using his close uncle Abu Talib(ابوطالب) to pressure him.
In this narration, we have over here,
Aqeel(عقيل), the son of Abu Talib(ابوطالب), he narrates and says that
the people of Quraish(قُرَيْشْ), they came to Abu Talib(ابوطالب), and they told him;
This nephew of yours is disrupting and disturbing us in our meetings and in our mosque.
So, they consider the Da'wah(دعوة) of Rasool Allah ﷺ to be disruption.
So, tell him to stay away from us.
Abu Talib(ابوطالب) told Aqeel(عقيل), go and call Muhammad(محمد) for me.
So, Aqeel(عقيل) said: I found him in Qanas(قَنَسْ),
Qanas(قَنَسْ) means, a very small room or a tent
and it was noon time very hot in Makkah.
So, Rasool Allah ﷺ came to meet his uncle Abu Talib(ابوطالب).
So, his uncle Abu Talib(ابوطالب) told him, that your people are complaining
and saying that you are disrupting them, and you are disturbing them in their meetings.
So, why don't you stop.
And Abu Talib(ابوطالب) was not speaking to Muhammadﷺ, in a tone of an order, do this!
But he was telling him as an advice, it's better, you know, so that you would not (harm or) have your people upset,
how about if you stop disturbing them or disrupting their meetings, in a very kind way.
Rasool Allah ﷺ told Abu Talib(ابوطالب)
Rasool Ullah, he looked at the sky and he pointed it to the sun and told Abu Talib(ابوطالب),
O my uncle, Do you see the sun?
He said: Yes.
Rasool Allah ﷺ said: I am no more capable of stopping that, than you are, of getting me a flame from it.
In other words, it's impossible for me to stop this.
Just like it is impossible for you to get a flame from this sun.
This is part of me, Da'wah(دعوة) is my life, spreading Islam is my mission,
I cannot give it up, it's impossible.
And you must have heard of the narration when Rasool Allah ﷺ says:
If they put the sun, on my right hand and the moon and my left hand
I would not give up this matter, until Allah سبحانه وتعالى judges or I lose my life.
That is a weaker narration.
But we find the same meaning in the strong narration.
That no matter what I will continue with this mission.
His uncle told him, O my nephew, you are telling the truth, I believe you, go ahead and continue.
So, Abu Talib(ابوطالب) was telling Muhammadﷺ, I believe you that you cannot give this up.
Go ahead, I will support you, do what Allah has told you to do.
We see from this, that the people of Quraish(قُرَيْشْ) are using every method, to try to sway Muhammadﷺ
and they would never give up, I mean, even when Rasool Allah ﷺ told the Sahabah(صحابه), and we gonna talk about next.
When the Messenger of Allah told the Sahabah(صحابه) to go to Al-Habasha(ألحبشه), to Abyssinia, so that they could flee from the persecution,
still Quraish(قُرَيْشْ) weren't satisfied with that and they sent a delegation to ask An-Najashi(أنجاشي) to turn the Muslims over,
Why.?
Were the Muslims in Abyssinia any threat to Quraish(قُرَيْشْ) politically?
No.
Were they, a threat economically? No.
So, what is the reason Quraish(قُرَيْشْ) are so persistent in following the Muslims even though the Muslims left them alone.
So, the issue here, even if Rasool Allah ﷺ would have stopped,
they wouldn't have left Rasool Allah ﷺ alone.
The people of Quraish(قُرَيْشْ) wanted to stop this message, by all means possible.
And if you would leave them alone, they won't leave you alone.
Number nine:  Jealousy and hatred,
Al-Waleed Bin Mugheera(الوليد بن مغيره), one of the elders of Quraish(قُرَيْشْ), he said;
If Allah wanted to choose a Prophet, how come he didn't choose me?
I'm more wealthy and wise and older than Muhammadﷺ,
and there was a similar claim made by a man in At-Taef(ألطائف),
now the two prominent towns of Hijaaz(حجاز) were Makkah and At-At-Taef(اَلطَّائِف).
So, Allah سبحانه وتعالى revealed the Ayah(آية),
وَقَالُوا لَوْلَا نُزِّلَ هَٰذَا الْقُرْآنُ عَلَىٰ رَجُلٍ مِنَ الْقَرْيَتَيْنِ عَظِيمٍ۝
Why wasn't this Qur'an revealed to a great man from one of the two towns,
referring to Makkah and At-Taef(اَلطَّائِف)?
Al-Mugheera Bin Sho'bah(المغيرة بن شعبه), who was from At-Taef(اَلطَّائِف),
he was visiting Makkah, and he said, and this Hadith(حديث) is narrated by Al-Bayhaqi(البيهقي).
Al-Mugheera Bin Sho'bah(المغيرة بن شعبه) said:
My first contact with Rasool Allah ﷺ happened one day, when I was walking with Abu Jahal(ابو جَهَل) in the streets of Makkah
and he ran into Muhammadﷺ.
So, he walked up to us, and he spoke to Abu Jahal(ابوجَهَل) and said:
Why don't you follow me, believe in Allah believe in Islam.
He was giving Abu Jahal(ابوجَهَل) Daw'ah(دعوة).
Abu Jahal(ابوجَهَل) responded by saying; O Muhammad(محمد), when are you going to stop cursing our gods?
If you want us to testify that you have fulfilled your mission, we will testify for you.
And if I knew that you were telling the truth, I would have already followed you, Muhammadﷺ left.
The meaning of the words of Abu Jahal(ابوجَهَل), if you want us to testify that you have fulfilled the message
because Rasool Allah ﷺ was telling them again and again that my role is to convey a message.
It is not my role to convert you, that is up to Allah.
All what I want to do is to fulfill my mission.
So, Abu Jahal(ابوجَهَل) was saying if you want us to witness for you, in front of Allah we'll do so.
We'll tell Allah that you have done your job, but just leave us alone.
Because if I knew that you were telling the truth, I would have already followed you.
So, Muhammadﷺ left,
AL-Mugheera(المغيره) said: Abu Jahal(ابو جَهَل) looked at me and said:
I know that he's saying the truth, but there's something holding me back.
The descendants of Qusa'e(قُصَئْ) said: We want to have Hijabah(حِجَابَهْ).
Remember, these are the honors of Quraish(قُرَيْشْ)
the power and the authority of Quraish(قُرَيْشْ).
We talked about it, when we talked about Qusa'e Bin Kalaab(قصئ بن كلاب), if you remember
AL-Hijabah(الحجابه) and Siqayah(سقايه), An-Nadwah(اَلنَّدوَةْ), An-Nadwah(اَلنَّدْوَة) means the assembly of Quraish(قُرَيْشْ),
AL-Hijabah(الحجابه) is the guardianship of Al-Ka'aba(اَلْكَعْبَه).
Sikayah(سقايه) and Rifadah(رفاده) is providing the pilgrims with food and water,
and the Luwaa(اللؤآء) is the banner of war.
So, Abu Jahal(ابوجَهَل) said: I know that this man is telling the truth, but there's something holding me back,
the descendants of Qusa'e(قُصَئْ) said, we want the authority of An-Nadwah(اَلنَّدوَةْ),
we gave it to them.
We want the authority of AL-Hijabah(الحجابه),
We want the authority of Luwaa(اَلُّؤآء),
we gave it to them,
we want the authority of Rifadah(رفاده) and Siqayah(سقايه),
we gave it to them.
And now when we started picking up and competing with them, and we were running neck to neck
they came up and say that we have a Prophet among us, how can we compete with that.
By God we never gonna accept this.
Abu Jahal(ابوجَهَل) is saying that this is a matter of competition, power struggle between us and the family of Rasool Allah ﷺ.
They have been given all of the authorities of Makkah.
And now we want to catch up with them, compete with them.
We can't compete with them and providing for the pilgrims and things like that, but we can't compete in Prophet hood.
None of us can compete with the Qur'an that is been given to Muhammadﷺ.
So, we're never going to admit that that's the truth.
Because if we do, that means they would have won against us.
So it's a matter of power, and authority.
So, you can see the element of jealousy and hatred, and not willing to give up power.
And that's why, you would find again and again in Qur'an, that's usually the ones, who are the most outspoken,
and violent in their rejection of the message of the prophets are the ones in authority, the people in power,
Why?
Because they feel that this is a message that will change the status quo
and will strip us from our abilities to take advantages of others and to enslave others.
This is a religion that will free people from worshipping people into worshipping Allah.
And these are referred to in Qur'an as Al-Malaa(ألملاء)
whenever you would have Al-Malaa(ألملاء) in Qur'an it is referring to the leadership.
وَقَالَ الْمَلَأُ مِن قَوْمِه
And this comes up with Firaoun(فرعون) it comes up with the people of Aad(عاد), Salih(صالح) you'd find that it is Al-Malaa(ألملاء).
Ten(10), persecution:
Now, even though Rasool Allah ﷺ was insulted and harmed and false accusations were directed towards him,
he was not persecuted.
And that is part of the protection, of the protection of Allah towards Muhammadﷺ.
Allah سبحانه وتعالى has protected Muhammadﷺ in the early years through his uncle Abu Talib(ابوطالب).
And later on, they would try to assassinate him and Allah سبحانه وتعالى would protect him,
even though his uncle Abu Talib(ابوطالب) has passed away.
So, Rasool Allah ﷺ wasn't really persecuted, but it was his followers, who were persecuted.
And this was the opinion of Ibn Is'haqq(اِبْنِ اِسْحَاقْ), he states that
he said that Allah has protected Muhammadﷺ because of His love of His messenger.
And Allah has protected him through his uncle Abu Talib(ابوطالب).
These are the words of Ibn Is'haqq(اِبْنِ اِسْحَاقْ).
But the persecution of the followers of Rasool Allah ﷺ used to hurt the Messenger of Allah a lot, because he cared about them so much.
And pretty much all of them, went through one form of persecution or another.
In one statement of Ibn Is'haqq(اِبْنِ اِسْحَاقْ), he says that
اَلْبَسُوْهُمْ اَدْرَعَلْ حَدِيْدْ وَسَحَرُهُمْ فِيْ الشَّمْسَ
They would wrap them up in shields of iron and leave them in the sun to burn.
So, they would cloth them in shields of iron, steel, and they would leave them in the hot sun of Makkah.
Now, the strongest among the Sahabah(صحابہ), in his response, in fighting the persecution was Bilal Bin Rabbah رضي الله عنه.
The more they would persecute him, the stronger he would become.
He was asked, how come when you were punished, and tortured, you would say Ahad-Ahad(احد احد),
Allah is one, Allah is one.
How come you chose that slogan?
Bilal(بلال) said: Because I found out that, when I would say Ahad-Ahad(احد احد)
it would make them the angriest.
This statement would anger them the most.
And that is why, I would say Ahad-Ahad(احد احد).
So, Bilal(بلال) wasn't looking for a way to reduce the punishment, he didn't care.
And the statement of Ibn Is'haqq(اِبْنِ اِسْحَاقْ) is
باعُ نَفْسَه لله
That he sold himself to Allah سبحانه وتعالى, he gave up his life to Allah.
He would say Ahad-Ahad(احد احد) and Umayyah Bin Khalaf(اميه بن خلف) would become angry
and would add the punishment, and Bilal(بلال) would only say it louder, wouldn't give up.
Now they went through different forms of torture.
And the torture was not only limited to the slaves and servants
but even some of the nobility were tortured.
Uthman Ibn Affan(عثمان بن عفان), belonging to one of the noblest families of Quraish(قُرَيْشْ), Bannu Umayyah(بَنُو اُمَيَّه),
he was wrapped in a carpet and then they would jump over him and crush him inside that carpet.
And you're familiar with some of the stories of persecution that happened to the slaves.
Like what happened to Sumayyah(سميه), and her husband and her son,
Yasser(ياسر), and Sumayyah(سميه) were both killed, under the severe tormenting of Abu Jahal(ابوجَهَل).
In one narration, it states that Abu Jahal(ابوجَهَل) struck Sumayyah(سميه) with a spear in her private parts, until he killed her.
And all of this was becoming so much on Sayyedina Ammar رضي الله عنه,
it's a combination of psychological pain and physical pain,
physical pain because of the tormenting was going through.
Plus seeing his mother and father go through this severe punishment and sad ending.
Ammar Bin Yasir(عمار بن ياسر) buckled under this pressure and he spoke some words against Muhammadﷺ.
Now, when he woke up from the pain, he went to Rasool Allahﷺ, sad and sorry for what has happened
and he narrated the incident to Muhammadﷺ.
Allah سبحانه وتعالى revealed an Ayah(آية) dealing with that particular situation,
saying that one is excused to speak some words with the tongue, under this torture if the heart is confident with faith,
if the heart is firm on Eeman(ايمان) and has Yaqeen(يقين) it is ok for a person to speak,
because
لَا يُكَلِّفُ اللَّهُ نَفْسًا إِلَّا وُسْعَهَا ۚ
Allah سبحانه وتعالى does not overburden a person.
This is unbearable pain that Ammar Bin Yasir(عمار بن ياسر) was going through.
So, this persecution continued with almost all of the Sahabah(صحابہ) with a few exceptions,
the ones who had some strong backing of their families and had some sympathy from some of their non believing relatives.
Now the severest in his punishment and the one who would actually mobilize the people of Quraish(قُرَيْشْ), was Abu Jahal(ابو جَهَل).
He was their leader in evil,
Ibn Is'haqq(اِبْنِ اِسْحَاقْ) states: "that sinner Abu Jahal(ابوجَهَل) was the one, who incited the men of Quraish(قُرَيْشْ) against them.
When he heard of a man of status and influence who had accepted Islam.
He would upbraid and insult him saying, you have abandoned the religion of your father, a man better than you.
We will depreciate your values, deride your opinions and destroy your reputation.
If the Muslim were merchant, he would say we will by God boycott doing business with you, and we will ruin you.
If the Muslim was defenseless Abu Jahal(ابوجَهَل) would beat him up and incite others against him,
may Allah damn and punishment him.
So, Abu Jahal(ابوجَهَل) was the spear head of the efforts of Quraish(قُرَيْشْ) against the Muslims in Makkah.
Number 11:
Forgot to mention Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمر ابن الخطاب),
Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمر ابن الخطاب), he had a slave girl that he would torture,
and sometimes he would stop.
And to show you, his personality, Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمر ابن الخطاب) when he would stop,
he would tell her, don't think that I'm giving you a break because I'm having sympathy on you.
The only reason why I stopped is because I'm tired.
Otherwise I would continue.
But
الله سبحانه وتعالى يَهْدِيْ مَنْ يَشَاءْ
Allah سبحانه وتعالى guides whomever He wills.
11) When the attempts of Quraish(قُرَيْشْ) of character assassinations failed.
They attempted to assassinate the character.
They tried to destroy the message by distorting the image of the messenger.
When that didn't work, they tried to eliminate the Messenger.
And these attempts occurred after Abu Talib(ابوطالب) passed away.
They knew that they have no way of assassinating Muhammadﷺ during the life of Abu Talib(ابوطالب).
But when he passed away, they attempted to assassinate him.
Allah سبحانه وتعالى says,
وَإِذْ يَمْكُرُ بِكَ الَّذِينَ كَفَرُوا لِيُثْبِتُوكَ أَوْ يَقْتُلُوكَ أَوْ يُخْرِجُوكَ ۚ
وَيَمْكُرُونَ وَيَمْكُرُ اللَّهُ ۖ وَاللَّهُ خَيْرُ الْمَاكِرِينَ۝
Allah سبحانه وتعالى says they attempted to drive you out of your land, to imprison you and to kill you.
So, the attempts were made but Allah سبحانه وتعالى would protect him,
and we'll talk about one of these attempts when we talk about Hijrah(هجرة).
So, these are the various methods that the people of Quraish(قُرَيْشْ) used at one time or another during the era of Makkah.
What was the response of Rasool Allahﷺ, how would he respond to all of this?
In Al-Bukhari(اَلبُخَارِي), Khabbab Ibn Arat(خباب ابن ارت), who was one of the Sahabah(صحابہ) who went through a lot.
He went to Rasool Allah ﷺ while the Messenger of Allah was leaning his back towards the Al-Ka'aba(اَلْكَعْبَه).
And he walked up to Muhammadﷺ and said,
يَا رَسُوْل الله اَلَا تَدْعُ لَنَا ، اَلَا تَسْتَنْصِرُلَنَا
O Messenger of Allah, Why don't you make Dua(دُعَا) for us?
That's all what he said.
But the message implies that we are going through a lot.
Why don't you ask Allah to ease the pain that we're going through.
And Khabbab Ibn Arat(خباب ابن ارت) was going through a lot himself.
One day later on, when Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمر ابن الخطاب) was the Khalifah(خليفه),
Umar(عُمَر) was asking all of the people around to talk about their experiences in Makkah.
What did you go through?
So, when the term came on Khabbab Ibn Arat(خباب ابن ارت), he didn't speak.
All what he did was, lift his shirt and expose his back. That's it!
Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمر ابن الخطاب) Said: I have never seen something like this.
What happened to you?
Khabbab Ibn Arat(خباب ابن ارت) had deep holes, deep black holes in his back.
He said when I was in Makkah, the people of Quraish(قُرَيْشْ) would bring some rocks and burn them over fire,
some small rocks and they would burn them on fire until they turn red.
And then they would lay them on the hot sand in the desert of Makkah, and they would throw me on top of it.
So, these rocks, they would burn through my flesh
and I would hear the burning of my flesh and I would smell my fat, grease is burning.
He said: I would smell the smoke coming off from my back.
So, Khabbab Ibn Arat(خباب ابن ارت) had something to complain about.
This was severe pain that he was going through, and all what he asked for is
يَا رَسُوْل الله ، اَلَا تَسْتَنْصِرُلَنَا
O Rasool Ullah, why don't you ask Allah to give us victory?
What was the response of Rasool Allah ﷺ.
Rasool Allah ﷺ he sat straight and his face turned red
and that would happen to Rasool Allah ﷺ, when he would become angry.
And then he said,
كَانَ يُؤتى بِمَنْ قَبْلَكُمْ
فَيُنْشَرْ الْمِنْشَارُ الْحَدِيدِ مَا بَيْنَ لَحْمِهِ أَوْ عَصَبِهِ وَ عَظَمِهِ،
فَلَا يَرُدَّه’ ذَلِكَ عَنْ دِينِهِ،
فَكَانَ يوتى بِاَحَدٍ فَيُوضَعُ الْمِنْشَارُ عَلَى مَفْرِقِ رَأْسِهِ فَيُشَقُّ بنصفين، فَلَا يَدَعُ دِينَه
وَلَيُتِمَّنَّ اللَّهُ هَذَا الأَمْرَ حَتَّى يَسِيرَ الرَّاكِبُ مِنْ صَنْعَاءَ إِلَى حَضْرَمَوْتَ،لَا يَخَافُ إِلاَّ اللَّهَ وَالذِّئْبَ عَلَى غَنَمِهِ
Rasool Allah ﷺ said: A believer among those who were before you, used to be combed with iron combs
that would separate the flesh and nerves from their bones.
So, you'd have iron combs, and they would comb the flesh of their bones.
But they would never desert their religion.
And they would bring one of them and place a saw on top of their heads,
and they would be cut into two halves.
And yet they would never give up their religion.
In the name of Allah, Allah will give His religion victory,
until a traveler will go from Sana'a(صنعاء) all the way to Hazaral Maot(حضرموت), fearing no one but Allah.
What can we learn from this Hadith(حديث).?
Number one, Rasool Allah ﷺ is asking us to be patient.
Be patient, even if you are going through a lot, be patient never give up,
All what Khabbab Ibn Arat(خباب ابن ارت) was going through, still Rasool Allah ﷺ is telling him be patient.
The second lesson, Allahسبحانه وتعالى has some laws,
just like there are laws in nature, there are laws of history,
there are laws of sociology, there are laws of psychology,
and there are laws in the establishment of religion.
And you will have to go through the stages and Allahسبحانه وتعالى will not give you an exception
you will have to go through what the nation's before you, went through.
This is what they went through.
The same will happen with you and Rasool Allah ﷺ wanted his Ummah(امة) to be the best of nations.
If the people before were patient, I want my Ummah(امة) to be more patient.
If the people before were strong, I want my people to be stronger.
And that's why Rasool Allah ﷺ was angry.
He wants the best to be in his Ummah(امة).
He wants his Ummah(امة) to show the best example.
He wants to be proud with us on the Day of Judgment.
Therefore, dear brothers or sisters, we have to live up to what Rasool Allah ﷺ expects from us.
He wants to meet us on the day of Judgment and see us and he wants to be proud with us.
And Rasool Allah ﷺ has stated this in a few Ahadith(احاديث).
For example, in one Hadith(حديث) Rasool Allah ﷺ says:
I want you to get married and to multiply, because I want to be proud with your numbers on the Day of Judgment.
He even wants to be proud with our numbers.
So he's asking us to have a lot of kids, and he's asking us to get married.
And Rasool Allah ﷺ in another Hadith(حديث),
I saw a huge nation in front of my eyes.
So, I asked the angels who are accompanying me, Is this my Ummah(امة)?
They said: No, this is not your Ummah(امة); this is the Ummah(امة) of Musa(موسى), these are Banni Israel(بني اسرائيل).
So, Banni Israel(بني اسرائيل) is the second largest Ummah(امة) after the Ummah(امة) of Muhammadﷺ, it's a huge numbers.
So, the greatest Ummah(امة) after the Ummah(امة) of Muhammadﷺ is the children of Israel(اسرائيل)
And then the Angels told me: Look at your right side.
So, I looked and I saw people filling the horizon.
They told me look at the left side and I looked and I saw people filling the horizon.
The angels told me, this is your Ummah(امة), in addition to them, Allah will give you 70,000, who will enter Paradise without going through reckoning.
Rasool Allah ﷺ said in another narration of the Hadith(حديث), that I was very impressed by their looks.
I was so impressed by their looks, I was proud
and the interpreters of the Hadith(حديث), the commentators of the Hadith(حديث) said,
Rasool Allah ﷺ was impressed because he saw on them, the signs of Sujood(سجود) and Wudhoo(وضؤ)
and that made light shine out of their faces.
So, Rasool Allah ﷺ loves this, he loves to see his Ummah(امة) in the best shape and form.
So, he is telling Khabbab Ibn Arat(خباب ابن ارت), you have to be patient, this is what happened to the people before.
You have to go through that, and you have to show a better example.
Third lesson, to be learned.
Rasool Allah ﷺ said: Allah will complete His religion
until a traveler will leave from Sana'a(صنعاء) all the way to Hazaral Maot(حضر موت) fearing no one but Allah.
How come Rasool Allah ﷺ chose Sana'a(صنعاء) and Hazaral Maot(حضر موت).?
Rasool Allah was in Makkah
why didn't he use Makkah as a reference point, since they were insecure.?
How cannot speak about their insecurity, how come Rasool Allah ﷺ is bringing an example from Yemen?
Both Sana'a(صنعاء) and Hazaral Maot(حضر موت) are in Yemen.
Now since this relates to somebody who's going so in security in Makkah,
how came Rasool Allah ﷺ didn't say Makkah and Madina, Makkah and Hajar(هَجَر), Makkah and Syria.
Or how come he didn't choose two reference points in another country?
How come Sana'a(صنعاء) and Hazaral Maot(حضر موت)?
There's something interesting in the choice of Rasool Allah ﷺ of these particular two areas in Yemen.
Yemen used to be and still is, a very tribal society.
And in the time of Rasool Allah ﷺ all of that area was covered by armed tribes, who had constant war between them.
And they were in rivalry and it was insecure.
When Islam entered into Yemen, during the time of Rasool Allah ﷺ Islam made the whole area peaceful.
Subhaan Allah(سُبْحَان الله) now, when people are getting away from Islam, and we're missing the Islamic rule,
that same area between Sana'a(صنعاء) and Hazaral Maot(حضر موت) today is one of the most insecure areas in Yemen.
And if somebody wants to travel through a particular route that will go through the tribal areas
between Sana'a(صنعاء) and Hazaral Maot(حزرالموت) forget about traveling, if you are not armed.
So it's, Subhaan Allah(سُبْحَان الله) very interesting that Rasool Allah ﷺ chose this area,
which is now one of the more insecure areas in the world as a reference, to say that you cannot have peace without Islam.
And this leads to the fifth lesson
that there is no comprehensive peace unless Islam reigns.
Under Islam, people will have true peace.
And that's the meaning of the word Islam, peace.
Another example that could reveal to us how Rasool Allah ﷺ used to deal with these situations of people of Quraish(قُرَيْشْ).
The people of Quraish(قُرَيْشْ), met together and said,
Let's find somebody who's the most experts in poetry and magic, to go and meet Muhammadﷺ and tell us how to deal with him.
So, they decided that they're going to send Utba Bin Rabiya(عتبة بن ربيعه), who was supposedly an expert in these areas.
Utba Bin Rabiya(عتبة بن ربيعه), he went to Muhammadﷺ and said tell me, O Muhammad(محمد), who is better, you or Abdul Muttalib(عبد المطلب).
These questions are a setup, in the society of Arabia.
They had so much respect and glorification for their ancestry.
And the family of Rasool Allah ﷺ was a lineage of nobility.
So, these were, held in very high esteem, not only among the family of Rasool Allah, but among everyone in Makkah.
Qusa'e Bin Kulaab(قصئ بن كلاب), Hashim(هاشم), Abdul Muttalib(عبدالمطلب), these were people, who were glorified.
And forget about speaking against any one of them.
You just can't do that; It's not allowed, unaccepted, not tolerated.
So Utba(عتبة), who is not a descendant of Bannu Hashim(بنو هاشم) is asking Muhammadﷺ,
What do you say about your father Abdullah(عبدالله), tell us what, what's your opinion about him?
What do you say about your grandfather Abdul Muttalib(عبد المطلب)?
These were setup questions.
He asked him about Abdullah(عبدالله).? Rasool Allah ﷺ remained silent, he didn't answer.
He asked him about Abdul Muttalib(عبد المطلب).? Rasool Allah ﷺ did not respond.
So, Utbah(عتبه) said: If you claim those men to be better than you the fact is they worship the gods you have criticized.
If you claim to be better than them, then speak so we can hear what you say.
By God, we've never seen any fool more harmful to his people than you.
You've caused division and dissension among us, criticized our religion
and so disgraced us in the eyes of the Arabs, that the rumor is current among them, that there is a magician or a sorcerer, amidst Quraish(قُرَيْشْ).
Now Utbah(عتبه) is blaming Muhammadﷺ for this rumor, that there is a sorcerer in Quraish(قُرَيْشْ).
Who founded, this rumor start with?
Who is the one, who went around telling the people that there's a sorcerer among us isn't that the leaders of Quraish(قُرَيْشْ) and among them Utbah(عتبة)
and now he's blaming Muhammadﷺ for it, because it affected them,
and it was an embarrassment for them.
They are the ones, who told the Arabs that he's a sorcerer and now it's an embarrassment for them.
Everyone among the other tribes are speaking about the sorcerer among Quraish(قُرَيْشْ).
Then he said;
By God, fellow it seems all we have to await, is the cry of a pregnant woman for us all to be at one another with swords, till we wipe ourselves out.
What he meant by this is, we're waiting for the cry of a pregnant woman meaning,
in a very short time, we might be fighting each other in Quraish(قُرَيْشْ), because of what you have brought?
You have caused disunity among us, we are about to jump at each other's throats.
And then he offered him similar offers.
What do you want status or wealth, whatever you want, we'll give it to you just tell us so that we can bring an end to this.
Rasool Allah ﷺ allowed Utbah(عتبة) to go on, with this nonsense, without interrupting him.
Rasool Allah ﷺ was a very good listener.
Even though all of this was stuff that didn't make any sense.
Rasool Allah ﷺ was calmly listening.
And when Utbah(عتبة) finished, Rasool Allah ﷺ asked him: O Utbah(عتبة), are you done?
Very kindly, are you done? He said: Yes.
Rasool Allah ﷺ, did not respond to what he was saying by his own words.
But he started reciting Ayaat(آيات) from Surah Al-Fusilat(سورة الفصلت).
In the beginning,
بِسْمِ اللَّهِ الرَّحْمَٰنِ الرَّحِيمِ۝
In the Name of God, the Most Merciful and beneficent
حم ۝
تَنْزِيلٌ مِنَ الرَّحْمَٰنِ الرَّحِيمِ ۝
كِتَابٌ فُصِّلَتْ آيَاتُهُ قُرْآنًا عَرَبِيًّا لِقَوْمٍ يَعْلَمُونَ۝
Ha(ح), Meem(م), A revelation from the Most Merciful and Beneficent,
a book whose verses have been detailed in an Arabic Qur'an for people who are aware,
and he went on going on and on it's about the page, quite a few Ayaat(آيات).
And he kept on reciting until he reached to a verse that states,
I warn you of a terrible punishment like that which destroyed Aad(عاد) and Thamood(ثمود).
In one narration, it says that when Rasool Allah ﷺ, mentioned this Ayah(آية).
Utbah(عتبة) placed his hand over the mouth of Rasool Allah ﷺ and urged him to stop.
Because this Ayah(آية) is threatening them with punishment.
And Utbah(عتبة) knew deep in his heart that Muhammadﷺ is truthful,
he never said, anything that did not come to happen
and if he is threatening us with punishment, it might come to happen.
So, I need to stop him and he said, I asked you in the name of the relationship between us to stop.
And in this other narration, it states that Utbah(عتبة), went back to the people and they told them what happened.
He said, he recited to me Qur'an and I did not understand anything he was saying,
except that he threatened us with a punishment like the punishment of Aad(عاد) and Thamood(ثمود),
they told him; Woe to you, he's speaking to you in Arabic and you don't understand him.
He said; In the name of Allah I did not understand, what he was talking about.
Well, the same Ayaat(آيات) say that some people have a seal over their heart, they will not understand it.
The lesson to learn from this is that Rasool Allah ﷺ dealt with different situations, different ways.
And many times he would use Qur'an to respond to what they were saying.
So, let's use Qur'an, let's use the concepts of Qur'an in our Da'wah(دعوة).
What is better to use, than the words of Allahعَزّ وجَلّ.
I'll talk about the story of the Dimaadh(ضماد),
Dimaadh Al-Asdi(ضماد الازدي) was a man from Azd-Shinwaa( أَزْدِ شَنُوءَةَ ) from Southern Arabia, he came into Makkah.
And he heard some of the people in Makkah saying that there is a man among us, who was obsessed with Jin(جن).
They were referring to Muhammadﷺ.
Dimaadh Al-Asdi(ضماد الازدي) used to be a man, who would heal people, who are obsessed with demons.
So, with the right intentions, Dimaadh Al-Asdi(ضماد الازدي) went to Rasool Allah ﷺ to offer his help.
He didn't mean anything bad, I mean, he never met Rasool Allah ﷺ, he doesn't know him.
Since he was an expert healer,
he went to Rasool Allah ﷺ and said: I heard that you are obsessed with Jin(جن) and I'm offering my service, if you want I can help you.
Which is a quite an insulting statement, but Rasool Allahﷺ, was a very compassionate
and he understood that this man might have heard some wrong information.
So, Rasool Allah ﷺ started by mentioning the words of Khut'ba-Tul-Haajah(خطبة الحاجة)
إِنَّ الْحَمْدَ لِلهِ، نَحْمدُهُ ونَسْتَعينُهُ وَنَسْتَغْفِرُهُ وَنَسْتَهْدِيْ،
وَنَعُوذُ باللهِ مِنْ شرورِ أَنْفُسِنَا وسَيِّئَاتِ أَعْمَالِنَا،
مَنْ يَهْدِهِ اللهُ فَلَا مُضِلَّ لَهُ، وَمَنْ يُضْلِلْ فَلَا هَادِيَ لَهُ
These are the words Rasool Allah ﷺ would usually start with, he would use these words as an opening of his speech.
So, Rasool Allah ﷺ just started with these words.
Let me translate them, Praise be to God, we praise Him and seek His help
whomever God leads a right! No one can lead astray.
Whomever God leads astray! No one can lead a right.
I bear testimony that there is no God but Allah alone, who has no associates.
The words in Arabic obviously have a rhyme to them and are quite eloquent, you lose that in translation.
But anyway, Dimaadh(ضماد) interrupted Rasool Allah ﷺ, he stopped him.
And he said: O, Muhammad(محمد), can you please repeat those words again.
Rasool Allah ﷺ repeated them again.
Dimaadh(ضماد) said; I have never heard something like this.
These words are so wonderful, they are going to reach the depths of the ocean,
meaning these words are going to have influence.
Rasool Allah ﷺ said, then pledge allegiance to me,
اُمدِدْ يَدَكَ اُبَايعكْ
Become a Muslim.
He immediately extended his hand and said:
اشهد ان لا إله إلا الله وأشهد ان محمد رسول الله
Rasool Allah ﷺ said: How about you also pledged for your people, your tribe.
He said: and I will pledge for my people.
Subhaan Allah(سُبْحَان الله) here you have a man, coming with one objective,
meeting Rasool Allah ﷺ for a few minutes, leaving as a Muslim.
He came to heal Rasool Allah ﷺ, Rasool Allah ﷺ healed him.
He went and left after this short meeting as a Muslim.
That was the personality that Rasool Allah ﷺ had, he had so much presence, so much influence on people
that within a short meeting it completely changes their lives.
I mean, this is a life changing event for Dimaadh(ضماد), becoming a Muslim.
It occurred within one meeting.
And this is a leadership quality that Allah سبحانه وتعالى has given Muhammadﷺ, he had this ability to influence others.
Subhaan Allah(سُبْحَان الله) years later, Rasool Allah ﷺ sent an army that passed next to the village of Dimaadh(ضماد).
The leader of the army, asked them did you take anything from these people.
So, one soldier in the army said: Yes, I have taken away from them, a strong camel.
The leader of the army said: Give it back because these are the people of Dimaadh(ضماد).
And Rasool Allah ﷺ has given them protection, give them back what belongs to them.
Another story with is a man called Amr Bin Absaa(عمرو بن عبسه),
Amr Bin Absaa(عمرو بن عبسه) was a man from Arabia, he wasn't from Makkah,
Amr Bin Absaa(عمرو بن عبسه) speaks about himself.
He mentions his story, it's in Sahih Muslim(صحيح مسلم).
He says, In the time of Jahilliyah(جاهليه), in the time of ignorance,
I had belief in my heart, that the religion of my people is false.
And I had no trust or belief in worshipping idols, I knew deep in my heart that this is wrong.
And then one day I came to know, that there was a man in Makkah, preaching a new religion.
So, I immediately went on my camel to meet him.
So, I came in, and Watalaftu(وَتَلَطَّفْتُ)  He said: I had to sneak in and secretly meet him.
That was how difficult the conditions were in Makkah, that a person from outside Makkah cannot meet Rasool Allah ﷺ publicly.
You can't even meet him, he said, Watalaftu(وَتَلَطَّفْتُ) I had to do it secretly.
And then I came to meet Rasool Allah ﷺ, I told him, What are you.?
He said, I'm a Prophet.
He said: What does that mean?
He said: I was sent by Allah.
What did he send you with?
And you can notice the simplicity of the Bedouin.
The mind is not complicated with philosophy and arguments and very simple.
What are you? I'm a Prophet.
What does that mean?
It means that I was sent by Allah.
What did He send you with.?
He said: He sent me with a message of worshipping Him alone, associating no Gods with Him.
and to destroy idols.
He said: Can I follow you.
Rasool Allah ﷺ said: You cannot follow me now; Don't you see my situation.
But go back to your people and when you hear that I prevail then come and see me.
Rasool Allah ﷺ knew that he will prevail one day.
He said: When you hear that I have prevailed, come and meet me.
So, Amr Bin Absaa(عمرو بن عبسه) said: I left and I would constantly ask about news, anything that relates to Muhammadﷺ.
The travelers, I was always asked them, what is happening with Muhammadﷺ.
Until one day I heard that Muhammadﷺ has migrated to Madina and he has been victorious.
So, I went to meet him in Madina.
He said; I approached Rasool Allah ﷺ and I asked him,
"Do you know me?".
This meeting now is years after he met with Rasool Allah ﷺ and he only met with Rasool Allah ﷺ for a very short time.
So, he went into Rasool Allah ﷺ and said: Do you know who I am?
Rasool Allah ﷺ said: Yes.
You are the man, who came and met me in Makkah.
And see that's another leadership quality.
You know your followers.
You remember them you remember their names, you know about them.
Sayyedina Sulaiman عليه السّلام was inspecting the army.
And his army was composed of humans, Jin(جن), birds.
So, it wasn't only restricted to one form of life, he had humans, Jin(جن), his Air Force was birds.
And he noticed the absence of one soldier, Al-Hud-Hud(ألهدهد).
One soldier was absent.
And only Allah knows the number of his army, but he noticed his absence.
Where is he.? He asked where's the Hud-Hud(هد هد).?
So, Rasool Allah ﷺ remembered Amr Bin Absaa(عمرو بن عبسه), years after he met him.
And he said: Yes, you are the man who came and met me Makkah.
Amr Bin Absaa(عمرو بن عبسه) said: O Messenger of Allah, teach me of that knowledge which Allah has taught you,
tell me about Salah( صلاة).
Rasool Allah ﷺ described how to pray.
And then he said, teach me about Wudhoo(وضؤ), and Rasool Allah ﷺ taught him Wudhoo(وضؤ).
صَلَّى الله عَلى سَيَّدِنَا محمد وَعَلى اَلِهِ وَ صَحْبِهِ وَسَلِّمْ تَسْلِيْمًا كَثِيْرًا